W: greghogan.uk

E: hire@greghogan.uk

L: Höngg, Zürich

I'm not a robot



#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### Exeon Analytics AG (60%) - Senior front-end developer

Feb 2021 - present

Senior front-end developer working with a mix of React and Redux building a security network analysis dashboard of graphs and data tables to help identify network intrusions and suspect network behaviour. Main responsibilities, polishing front end features developed by backend developers, creating a component library and style guide for the whole UI.

React, Redux, Styled components, JavaScript.

## Geeiq (40%) - Senior front-end developer

May 2020 - present

Senior front-end developer working with Ember and Ember Data, building a data dashboard with graphs and data tables for marketeers to determine appropriate esports streamers for their brand. Main responsibilities of developing new features as well as establishing a style guide and creating a reusable component library.

Ember.js, Ember CLI, Ember Data, JavaScript, Sass.

# Loveholidays - Front-end developer

November 2018 – *May 2020* 

Sub-team lead Front-end developer working among a velocity focused team as a part of the "experiments team". Using technologies such as ReactJS, Redux, React Hooks, and styled components to AB test variations of UI elements as well as UX journeys based on designs from the design team.

- ReactJS (Hooks, Styled Components), Redux, Redux-Saga, Immutable.JS, MochaJS, Enzyme, Jest, Chai assertion library, Sass, JavaScript, Optimizely.
- Created numerous UI components to aid in standardising page layout as well as recurring UI elements such as iconography, titles, etc.
- Helped to refactor numerous components in regard to JavaScript and HTML markup with an eye to improving readability and efficiency.

#### Movidiam Ltd - Senior Front-end developer

Sep 2013 - Apr 2014 (Freelance) / Dec 2014 - Jun 2018

Senior Front-end developer managing a small team. Liaising daily with the product owner, back-end development team and design team for a component based social networking / project management web app with 17K+ users.

- Sass, Ember.js, Ember CLI, Ember Data, JavaScript and jQuery.
- Revamped the HTML markup to modern semantic standards, implemented Sass and aided in establishing a codebase standard for CSS and JavaScript.
- Led a small team of developers working within an Agile development process with daily scrums and retrospectives once a feature was live.
- Worked with the design team to vet designs against potential web technology limitations as well as helped transition these designs to a responsive layout.

#### **SKILLS**

## Programming and technical

HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3, Sass, ReactJS (Hooks, Styled Components), Ember.js (Ember CLI, Ember Data, MochaJS, Enzyme, Chai assertion library, NPM, Yarn, Gulp, Webpack, UI / UX design

## **Experience with**

AngularJS, Redux, Redux-Saga, TypeScript

# Source control and user experience optimisation software

Git, GitHub, Jenkins, JIRA, Trello, Fullstory, Optimizely

## **Graphics software**

Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch, Final Cut Pro

#### Soft skills

Team lead, project management, interpersonal skills, keen eye for detail

- Created page templates for Salesforce which integrated submission forms and were consistent with the main website.
- Developed responsive HTML email templates which improved clickthrough rates by an average of 20%.

## Teads Ltd - Designer / Front-end developer

Apr 2014 - Dec 2014

Worked in an agency environment as a Developer / Designer on small projects and microsites as well as static Photoshop templates and graphics for advertisement briefs.

- JavaScript, jQuery, GreenSock animation, Photoshop and Flash.
- Developed a boilerplate for standard video microsite with full video event tracking, able to be integrated with Google Analytics or Teads internal tracking software.
- Created Photoshop templates for full-screen takeover graphics that were distributed to global Teads branches.
- Designed numerous microsites serving various promotional purposes as part of larger marketing campaigns.
- Communicated with clients directly alongside the account managers to establish the client requirements and offer solutions to match their needs.

#### **PROFILE**

A seasoned Front-end developer with a keen eye for well designed, performant and elegant user experiences and interfaces. Expert in accessible, semantic markup and CSS from modern to legacy browsers. Solid understanding that a product should work well before it can look good, but that the overall brand aesthetic is still crucial. Well versed in modern JavaScript frameworks based on a solid foundation of core JavaScript understanding and a keen learning instinct. Proud owner of an unhealthy obsession with CSS.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **BSc (Hons) Computer Games Production (2:1)**

2006 - 2009

Wide variety of modules covering design and technical skills. Focus on UI design and good UX practises. Advanced learning of industry standard software including but not limited to Photoshop, Illustrator, Maya and Web technologies (HTML, CSS, JavaScript).

# The Sixth Form College Farnborough (A-Levels)

2003 - 2005

Computing, English Language and Literature, Psychology

#### **REFERENCES**

**Peter Harrison** - Loveholidays **George Olver** - Movidiam

Available on request E: george@movidiam.com